{
    "id": "efdbc2c2ef854b639219f6deba81407a",
    "title": "Passive Voice Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The living room .............................. now.",
            "description": "We make the passive form of the present continuous tense with is/am/are + being + past participle.",
            "answers": [
                "is decorating",
                "has decorated",
                "is being decorated"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "cfc6ef08e236496e95183c67256b1d5c"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Olympic Games .............................. every four years.",
            "description": "They hold the Olympic Games every four years. The Olympic Games are held every four years. The passive form in the simple present tense is made with is/am/are + past participle.",
            "answers": [
                "are holding",
                "are held",
                "have hold"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a93abc2f167f4912924d7b302fee0f19"
        },
        {
            "question": "The patient ............................... on yesterday.",
            "description": "The passive form of the simple past tense is made with was/were + past participle. ",
            "answers": [
                "has operated",
                "was operated",
                "was being operated."
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "34fc37cbb47a434ca3e1389996d55087"
        },
        {
            "question": "By the end of this week, the roof .............................",
            "description": "They will repair the roof / The roof will be repaired. ",
            "answers": [
                "will repair",
                "will be repaired",
                "will be repairing"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "722bd51fb44c46458376733ff81f7652"
        },
        {
            "question": "The house ............................... when it collapsed.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was renovating",
                "was being renovated",
                "was renovated"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "fd7fff749d324d349e4be46a67909548"
        },
        {
            "question": "Criminals .................................. before they commit crimes.",
            "description": "Criminals will not stop. They should be stopped. The passive form of should stop is should be stopped.",
            "answers": [
                "should stop",
                "should be stopped",
                "should be stopping"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1e46cc34e21f402d8d00636056fefce5"
        },
        {
            "question": "I .................................. by the aroma of the freshly baked cookies.",
            "description": "The passive form of tempted is was tempted. ",
            "answers": [
                "was tempting",
                "was tempted",
                "have tempted"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4310743ceec547e082f0df41545ccde8"
        },
        {
            "question": "He .............................. to an uninhabited island.",
            "description": "They deported him. He was deported. ",
            "answers": [
                "was deporting",
                "deported",
                "was deported"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "bab51e0412cd41479c6102be85dc3041"
        },
        {
            "question": "The suspect .................................. by the police.",
            "description": "The police are interrogating the suspect. / The suspect is being interrogated by the police. ",
            "answers": [
                "is interrogating",
                "has interrogated",
                "is being interrogated"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3069b50780dc4942876ef3784ce3da31"
        },
        {
            "question": "The old building ................................. by the municipal authorities.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was demolished",
                "was demolishing",
                "is demolishing"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "bb3bd366181c4e35905cff78ed317d75"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ............................... to study physics at university.",
            "description": "They encouraged me. / I was encouraged. ",
            "answers": [
                "encouraged",
                "was encouraging",
                "was encouraged"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "553cd7f70ffb4d2797562425112ba1fe"
        },
        {
            "question": "The apples ...................................... when they are ripe.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "are picking",
                "are picked",
                "have picked"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "be996baedf1c4e079644f23cef3a93a0"
        }
    ]
}